"The Stranger I Met" Episode 12
《我遇见的陌生人》 第12集
(Wu Jindong)
（吴金东）
(Kyung Gi Joo)
（京基珠）
"A Stranger I Met"
《我遇见的一个陌生人》
Do you remember these people?
你还记得这些人吗？
May 14, 1987
1987年5月14日
Two female victims were killed in turn
两名女性受害者轮流被杀
The girl who has not yet been found
至今仍未找到的 女孩
This was the list of prime suspects at the time.
这是当时的 主要嫌疑人名单
The first suspect is Baksa
第一个嫌疑人是巴克萨
The second suspect is Yu Bum Yong
第二名嫌疑人是Yu Bum Yong
The third suspect?
第三个嫌疑人？
Gomin Su jailed for 30 years
被监禁30年的Gomin Su
Hello
你好
(Bangbang Teahouse)
（邦邦茶馆）
Almost impossible with those fingers
用那些手指几乎不可能
I am currently unable to do any form of bundling
我目前 无法进行任何形式的捆绑
Both are wearing red ties
两人都系着红色领带
Because I found it
因为我找到了
Yubum's fear has nothing to do with murder
Yubum的恐惧 与谋杀无关
Red body (communism).
红体（共产主义）。
Afraid of being caught if I don’t report it
怕不举报被抓
Is this what you're afraid of?
这就是你所害怕的吗？
Covering up a crime is not murder
掩盖罪行不是谋杀
Not arresting college students who commit crimes worse than murder
不逮捕犯下比谋杀更严重 罪行的大学生
You must come with us now
你现在必须跟我们一起去
Looking for your brother Bayusup
寻找你的兄弟巴尤苏普
( Suspect in Wu Jong-il serial murder case )
（吴宗日连环杀人案 嫌疑人）
(Episode 12 - The Absent One)
（第 12 集 - 缺席的人）
who I am?
我是谁？
Who do you think I am?
你觉得我是谁？
Article (12)
第 (12) 条
(Deadline for reporting suspects)
（举报嫌疑人的期限）
what are you saying?
你在说什么？
who do i want to be
我希望成为谁
Why are you here?
你为什么来这里？
If you really want to know who I am
如果你真的想知道我是谁
go to police station
去警察局
We found this at home
我们在家里发现了这个
in our garage
在我们的车库里
There are many strange things
还有很多奇怪的事情
Very strange person
很奇怪的人
Tell the police to identify
告诉警察辨认
This can also be done
这也可以做到
Have you finally come to me?
你终于来找我了吗？
because i can't do it
因为我做不到
Yes or no
是不是
- Hey, come on - Come on
- 嘿，快点 - 快点
Let's go quickly
我们快点走吧
- where - here
- 哪里 - 这里
- Hey - Hey guys
- 嘿 - 嘿家伙
- Finally caught this guy - Ha!
- 终于抓住了这个家伙 - 哈！
- What the hell happened - Back off
- 到底发生了什么 - 退后
what do you do now?
你现在做什么？
Already found
已经找到了
I have found
我已经找到了
(Bangbang Teahouse)
（邦邦茶馆）
Because I thought there wasn't
因为我以为没有
Otherwise it would be fine
不然就好了
That's because I thought of it
那是因为我想到了
Because only then will you know what you really want to know
因为只有这样你才会知道你真正想知道什么
Is this why you came to me?
这就是你来找我的原因吗？
No need to go to the police station
无需去警察局
If you really need an answer, my answer is no
如果你真的需要答案， 我的答案是否定的
Although I can't explain everything here
虽然我无法在这里解释一切
I won't do anything you suspect
我根本不做你怀疑的事情
I do not believe you
我不相信你
is that so
是这样吗
I can not afford it
我买不起
but..
但..
if you hide it
如果你隐藏它
You will be able to continue repairing the car
你将能够继续修理这辆车
Now what does this matter?
现在这有什么关系呢？
if you do
如果你这样做
I don’t know if you can solve it yourself.
不知道你能不能自己解决
who I am?
我是谁？
What is this all about?
这是什么一回事呢？
Why, what happened?
为什么，出了什么事？
What's wrong?
怎么了？
(Bangbang Teahouse)
（邦邦茶馆）
My fault
我的错
Be careful when entering and exiting the house
进出房子一定要小心
Don't worry
不用担心
times..
回..
This means that it will be temporarily overwritten
这意味着暂时会被覆盖
Although it will be because of the car and not because of me
虽然会因为车而不是因为我
How are you?
你还好吗？
Walk?
走？
Although we don't have much time
虽然我们没有太多时间
but also
但是也
I think it's time for a little breeze
我想是时候吹点微风了
i met my family
我见到了家人
That is..
那是..
Facing an unfamiliar family member’s face
面对一张不太熟悉的 家人的脸
I don't think it's an easy thing
我认为这不是一件容易的事
Although I haven’t traveled that far in time and space
虽然我没有去到时空旅行那么远
I'm a little older when it comes to family here.
说到这里的家人， 我年纪大了一些
Scarier than I imagined
比我想象的更可怕
I know I'll be nervous
我知道我会紧张
It's the same here with my mom
我妈妈这里也是这样
with my father..
与我的父亲..
face to face from time to time
时不时面对面
various questions
各种各样的问题
Is your mind confused?
你脑子里很困惑吗？
But that matchbox
但那个火柴盒
I think it's good that I found my dad and not someone else
我认为我找到了我的父亲而不是其他人， 这很好
I wasn't released because of my car.
我因为车没有被释放
I think
我认为
Although I can't explain it in words
虽然我无法用言语解释
I want to believe your feelings
想要相信你的感觉
There will definitely be
肯定会有
I have no idea
我不知道
The principal also said that he loved her very much
校长也说他很爱她
Because some things are attractive
因为有些东西很有吸引力
How do I identify this strange man?
我如何辨别这个陌生男人？
I feel the atmosphere of grandson
我感受到了孙子的气氛
Even though I know you want to comfort me
尽管我知道你想安慰我
I guess I just did something wrong
我想我只是做错了
Well
唔
I feel the atmosphere of grandson
我感受到了孙子的气氛
If that's the case, you'll be disgusted and hated from an early age
如果是这样的话， 你从小就会被厌恶和憎恨
Although he is the only family member who comes to accompany him
尽管他是唯一来陪伴他的家人
my life
我的一生
The person who treats me like I don't exist
那个对待我就像我不存在一样的人
How is it going?
最近好吗？
I have no idea
我不知道
I don't know what makes me so upset
我不知道是什么让我如此心烦意乱
But why alone?
但为什么孤身一人呢？
Don't you live with your father?
你没和你父亲住在一起吗？
I don’t know if I was shocked after my mother left.
不知道妈妈走后是否受到打击
Return to the United States
返回美国
He went on to school and became a professor
他继续上学并 成为一名教授
I've lived there my whole life
我一生都住在那里
Because he only comes back to see me on vacation
因为他只在放假的时候才 回来见我
I only see him twice a year
我一年只见他两次
Even then, I had to do research
即使在那个时候，我也必须做研究
Stayed for a while and then went back
停留了一段时间就回去了
Although he is a kind person
虽然是个善良的人
Until I feel like I want to believe when I'm free
直到我觉得我想要在自由的时候相信
I think I don't have enough bonds
我认为我没有足够的羁绊
Did I say too much?
我是不是说太多了？
i will be alone
我会独自一人
no one loves Me
没有人爱我
The time I thought like this
我这样思考的时光
But you know what?
但你知道吗？
i have a bond
我有一个债券
I think this is how I treat you
我想我对你就是这样的态度
the dream i dream
我所梦想的梦想
Take a time travel machine
乘坐时光旅行机
back to the Future
回到未来
Everything is as I imagined
一切都如我想象的那样
Miracle
奇迹
How come you have such good eyes?
你怎么有这么好的眼睛？
everyone seems happy
每个人似乎都很高兴
but..
但..
he's not there
他不在那儿
I didn't find much money
我没找到多少钱
You are definitely...
你绝对是..
That world doesn't exist
那个世界上不存在
disappeared without a trace
就消失得无影无踪
He woke up after searching all this time
他在一直寻找之后 醒来
This is my nightmare now
这就是我现在的 噩梦
Although I think this is a dream of freedom
虽然我觉得这是一个自由的梦
I'm disgusted and don't want to express it in words
我很反感，不想用言语表达
i feel scared and sad
我感到害怕和悲伤
the future without you
未来没有你
I want to have a future with you
我想和你有未来
There
那里
I will also take you to a good restaurant I know
我也会 带你去我知道的好餐厅
We will walk on a new road together
我们将一起走在新的路上
useless
无用
Not scary things, but lighthearted words
不是可怕的事情，而是 轻松的话语
I think I want to do it with you
我想我想和你一起做
Is this false comfort?
这是虚假的安慰吗？
this time
这次
Should I take that as comfort?
我应该把它当作安慰吗？
hehe
呵呵
I thought this was what I expected
我以为这正是我所期望的
such a future
这样的未来
So I pretended not to know until the end
所以直到最后 我才假装不知道
Although we don't have much time
虽然我们没有很多时间
A little while..
一小会儿..
They think things have stopped
他们认为事情已经停止了
I'm coming
来了来了
- I'm coming
- 来了
(The trustworthy Wujiang Police Station will always be with the people)
（值得信赖的吴江派出所，永远与人民在一起）
come out
出来
The real culprit?
真正的罪魁祸首是？
- Give me a word - Take it away
- 给我一句话 - 把它拿走
- Okay - go away
- 好吧 - 走开
- Remove - Do not push
- 移除 - 请勿推动
The real culprit?
真正的罪魁祸首是？
Rope found at the scene
现场发现绳索
The matchbox is out
火柴盒出来了
Why are you jumping to conclusions?
你为什么要急于下结论？
Currently, the suspect is the culprit
目前，嫌疑人已是罪魁祸首
If the culprit is most likely
如果罪魁祸首很可能是
Is that so, Detective Jane?
是这样吗，简侦探？
Did Detective Jane himself catch him?
简侦探本人抓住了他吗？
Although yes
虽然是的
wait
等待
From time to time he wrote articles slandering our battalion commander.
他时不时地写文章诽谤我们营长。
Mom, that's it
妈妈，就这样吧
Now I have to go to my post as originally planned.
现在我要按照原计划去岗位了
I turned a crisis into an opportunity
我把危机变成了机遇
- Now, give way. - Give way.
- 现在，让路 - 让路
- Give me a word - Delete
- 给我一句话 - 删除
Well, that's right
恩，那就对了
Yes, I think it's coming now
是的，我想现在就来了
- Yes, as soon as possible.. - Sit down
- 是的，尽快.. - 坐下
- I'll kill it. - Sit down.
- 我会杀了它
- Yeah - sitting here.
- 是的 - 坐在这里
Minsu
闽苏
you are the culprit
你才是罪魁祸首
This guy
这家伙
Yes
是的
- Yes , ma'am.
- 是的 ，夫人
How much had this guy drank?
这家伙喝了多少酒？
Why confess without knowing?
为何在不知情的情况下坦白？
I admit it's just because I drink
我承认只是因为我喝酒
Misu
米苏
Where is my sister Misu?
我的妹妹米苏在哪里？
Hey, let him sleep first
哎，让他先睡吧
If you regain consciousness, straighten up immediately
如果您恢复知觉，请立即直起身子
As soon as possible
尽快完成
- Yes Yes
- 是的 是的
hey guys
嘿家伙
- Be careful, hey - Mom
- 小心一点，嘿 - 妈妈
I have to go home now
我现在得回家了
- To - Miss this person
- 致 - 想念这个人
- leader - keep
- 领导者 - 保持
I have something to say
我有话要说
I found the matchbox, but no news
我找到了火柴盒，但 没有消息
I'll add the text from there
我将从那里添加文本
Isn't the fact that there is an empty match important?
存在空匹配这一事实不是 很重要吗？
Prepare in advance
提前准备好
(For better public policing)
（为了更好的公共警务）
I looked at the notebook in Gominsu's room
我看了看Gominsu房间里的笔记本
The handwriting is completely different
笔迹完全不一样
Have you taken the exam?
你考试了吗？
If it were you, would you write as usual?
如果是你，你会像平常一样 写作吗？
I can write the key
我会写钥匙
This definitely needs to be checked again
这肯定需要再次检查
Hey badminton number eight
嘿羽毛球八号
A child saw it with his own eyes
有小朋友亲眼所见
What else should I check?
又要检查什么？
What idiot would turn his family over to the police if it weren't for you ?
如果不是你，哪个白痴 会把家人交给警察？
As long as there are reliable witnesses and evidence
只要有可靠的目击者和 证据
This game is over
这场比赛已经结束了
I remember it was pretty good before
我记得以前还不错的
I have a knockout
我有淘汰赛
I'm short of water
我缺水了
strength
力量
it won't disappear
它不会消失
accused arrested
被告被捕
Your mother and future definitely saved me
你的母亲和未来 肯定拯救了我
we will go back together
我们会一起回去
Let's go shopping together for a long time
让我们一起逛很久
with me
与我一起
grandfather
祖父
Mother
母亲
- Is it dark? - Mother
- 天黑不黑？ - 妈妈
grandfather?
爷爷？
I?
我？
Did you get a call from your grandpa?
你接到你爷爷的电话了吗？
Okay, I have to go back
好吧，我得回去了
I want to enter
我要进入
moment
片刻
Teacher Ho..
何老师..
we sing
我们唱歌
he became a novelist
他成为一名小说家
Really good, yes
真的很好， 是的
Mom, that's it
妈妈，就这样吧
this is a big problem
这是一个很大的问题
Yes
是的
But good news
不过好消息
Because no one can boast
因为没有人可以夸耀
because people will laugh at
因为人们会嘲笑
She said she was not happy about her daughter's death.
她表示，女儿去世 让她不太高兴
But the matter of honor must be respected
但荣誉问题 必须得到尊重
Congratulations, I'm so proud
恭喜你，我很自豪
Thanks
谢谢
What our second daughter wants to do is education
我们二女儿想做的 教育
I wonder if I should continue teaching
我想知道我是否应该继续教书
Yes
是的
do it
做吧
I want to enter
我要进入
yes listen
是的，听着
real
真的
(Bangbang Teahouse)
（邦邦茶馆）
( Main suspect in serial murder case arrested)
（连环杀人案 主要嫌疑人被捕）
Ge Minsu...
戈敏苏..
I don’t know if anyone has been arrested yet.
不知道现在有没有被捕
if you have been arrested
如果您已经被捕
difficult to release immediately
很难立即释放
police..
警察..
no easy way out
没有简单的出路
Because the person who reported what he saw was a family member
因为报告亲眼所见 的人是家庭成员
Who could doubt this?
谁会怀疑这一点呢？
The real culprit in the end...
最后的真正罪魁祸首..
I think it will be released only after providing strong evidence.
我认为只有拿出有力证据后才会 发布
Gomin Su was murdered three or four hours before
Gomin Su被谋杀 前三、四个小时
he was seriously injured
他受了重伤
- That's when - Ms.
- 正是从那时起 - 女士
- Completely lost - Broken arm
- 完全迷失 - 手臂骨折
He reappeared unharmed and was arrested
他毫发无损地再次出现并 被捕
- Natalie - all this stuff.
- 娜塔莉 - 所有这些东西
It’s not enough that Hou Guang planned it himself
光是后光自己策划的还不够
Until then, the Gomi Prize Program
在那之前，五味奖计划
That night was a murder
那天晚上是一场谋杀
Until Gominsu hid this situation from others
直到Gominsu 向别人隐瞒了这样的情况
That's what everything we do means
这就是我们所做的一切的意义
It must be a very busy night
这一定是一个非常忙碌的夜晚
Five Flavors Award
五味奖
Not a false witness
不是假证人
It would be nice if real witnesses could come out
如果真正的目击者能出来就好了
This is Kim Hye Yeon
这是金惠妍
he looks scared
他看起来很害怕
If the Five Flavors novel is true
如果五味小说是真的
I'll see something myself
我自己会看到一些东西
But I don't know what will be different now
但我不知道现在 会有什么不同
Although I didn’t believe it before
虽然之前我也不相信
Because I saw that Gomin Su was actually arrested
因为我看到Gomin Su实际上被捕了
(Suspect in serial murder case arrested)
（连环杀人案嫌疑人 被捕）
Did you see it by the river?
你在河边看到了吗？
A red rope is tied around his wrist
一条红绳系在他的手腕上
Did that third brother come out of the room?
那个三哥是 从房间里出来的吗？
Some people actually see what they read in the newspapers
有些人确实看到了他们在报纸上读到的内容
kill
杀戮
- Ha - I feel bad for Mi Joo.
- 哈 - 我为美珠感到难过
He also said it was disgusting and terrible
他还说 这很恶心和可怕
It's all because of his brother
这一切都是因为他的兄弟做的
In fact, it was not Wuguang, the son of Apaha, who was pitied
其实， 被可怜的并不是五光，阿帕哈之子
He stole San Air's novel
他偷了桑艾尔的小说
His brother also killed his sister
他的哥哥也杀了他的妹妹
But I feel sad for Miju
但我为Miju感到难过
Why pity?
为何怜惜？
indeed
确实是
I didn't say anything, I just came here to blow some air.
我什么也没说， 只是来这里吹吹风
I will come to my mother's shop every time and sit there for free
我每次都会来妈妈的店里 免费坐
I said I know absolutely nothing
我说我绝对什么都不知道
Why do you bother me every now and then?
为什么要时不时地 打扰我？
I know I know I don't ask any more questions
我知道我知道我不再问什么了
I didn't do this to hurt you
我这样做不是为了伤害你
Excellent
出色地
If you are afraid of the police, tell your teacher
如果你害怕警察， 请告诉老师
one way or another
不管怎样
Mother
母亲
Do not talk
别说话
I said I'm no longer friends
我说我不再是朋友了
you..
你..
Are you dating Lee Seung Yeol?
你在和李承烈交往吗？
ha
哈
no no
不，不
Not because of dissatisfaction
不是因为不满意
tell me through this
通过这个告诉我
This is Lee Sun Alhara
这是李善阿尔哈拉
I want to return it myself, it was the head teacher who took it.
我要自己还， 是班主任拿的
but..
但..
I don't think he wants to see me
我认为他不想见我
I think I've become a very bad person
我想我已经成为一个很坏的人了
from now on
今后
went well
进行得顺利
If you don't want to be a worse person
如果你不想成为一个更坏的人
Think this is the last chance
认为这是最后的机会
correct
正确的
even if you don't send
即使你不发送
Why did you receive a class slip?
为什么你会收到班级单？
doctor..
医生..
When I was discharged from the hospital, I was told to walk more.
当我出院时，我被告知要多走路。
Being alone would be boring
一个人呆着会很无聊
will you go home?
你会回家吗？
Excellent
出色地
So let's come back in a week
所以我们一周后 回来吧
Lee Sun El...
李善艾尔..
Did you go back early?
你早回去了吗？
Excellent
出色地
Do you feel this way?
你有这么感触吗？
Is my sister dead?
我姐姐死了吗？
for other family members
对于其他家庭成员
accused arrested
被告被捕
demand repayment of debt
要求偿还债务
Probably the most anticipated one, right?
应该是最期待的 吧？
But why does this happen?
但为什么会发生这样的事呢？
But it will be sad
但 会很难过
I really don't know anything
我真的什么都不知道
Will they last a week?
他们会持续一周吗？
The school is empty anyway
无论如何，学校都是空的
Did they go away happy?
他们走得开心吗？
Are you going to the skating rink?
你要去溜冰场吗？
very good
很好
So are you going to a game store?
那你要去游戏店吗？
Do you know the skeleton game?
你知道骷髅游戏吗？
Although I feel a little sad because the baby is so cute
虽然心里有点难过 因为宝宝太可爱了
But if I do, I'll feel relieved
但如果我这样做了， 我就会感到轻松
let it be
随它去
so..
所以..
Do I have to give it to you from time to time?
我要时不时给你吗？
These
这些
- I.. - I'm going home today
- 我.. - 我今天要回家
our mother alone
我们的母亲独自一人
I'll go in first
我先进去
In the morning, after hearing the news of Su Wumin’s arrest,
早上，听到苏五民被捕的消息后
Our mother washed the dishes without saying a word
我们妈妈一言不发地 洗了碗
Take out all the dishes
把所有的菜都拿出来
I kept washing until I came out
我一直在洗直到我出来
at present
目前
A bunch of clothes to wash
一堆衣服要洗
From my room to Obo's room
从我的房间到Obo的 房间
Our mothers are like this too when they are angry
我们的妈妈生气的时候也是这样
if i miss my mother
如果我想我的妈妈
sometimes i get worried and scared
有时我会担心和害怕
So give me a hug
所以 给我一次拥抱吧
Mother
母亲
i nap till late
我小睡到很晚
I'm hungry
我饿了
Can I make your favorite topoki?
我可以做你最喜欢的topoki吗？
Oh, the printer sent something
噢，打印机发送了一些东西
Pre-copy or what?
预拷贝还是什么？
because of your book
因为你的书
I look a little curious
我看上去有点好奇
(Lee Seon-ah's "Small Door")
（李善阿尔《小门》）
your sister will love it
你姐姐会喜欢的
- Father - Yeah
- 父亲 - 嗯
- Mr. Yin.. - Mr. Yin, what's the matter?
- 尹先生.. - 尹先生，什么事？
We are not villagers
我们不是村民
what kind of person?
什么样的人？
Oh, what a strange man
噢，真是个奇怪的人
What's weird?
有什么奇怪的？
So all the time...
所以一直..
I'm saving people
我在救人
Priest
牧师
So the first day we met
所以我们见面的第一天
Three or four students in our school inhaled the superglue
我们学校三四名学生 吸入了强力胶
Still foamy
依然是泡沫状
A man is about to jump off the cliff
一个人正要从悬崖上 跳下去
My mother really doesn't want to die
我妈妈真的不想死
But he suddenly came and saved me
但他突然跑来 救了我
this is silly
这很傻
Then one day the village caught fire
然后有一天，村庄着火了
Mom, my heart is really
妈妈我的心真的
By the way, do you know Uncle Dongshi?
对了，你认识东石叔叔吗？
his children are there
他的孩子们在那里
But Yin saved me again
但尹再次救了我
this is silly
这很傻
not only
不仅
He suddenly appeared throughout the village, saved people, and then disappeared again
他突然出现在整个村子里， 救了人们，然后又消失了
If you think about it, to save someone
如果你想一想， 为了拯救一个人
this is not an easy task
这不是一件容易的事
This has been the case from the beginning
从一开始就是这样的情况
It's hard to appear in front of you
出现在你面前 很难
Yes or no
是不是
So is this weird or stupid?
那么这是奇怪还是愚蠢的呢？
Weird and stupid
奇怪又愚蠢
what exactly is it?
到底是什么？
As for Kim Hye-yeon, no matter what she says, she can't get enough help
至于金惠妍， 无论她说什么，都无法得到足够的帮助
Because you can't be forced to say it
因为你不能被迫说出来
we have to find another way
我们必须找到另一种方式
Ho...
嗬..
teacher
老师
well said
说得好
for real..
真正的..
Did it or didn’t say it?
做了没说
I know
我知道
Because I was told to keep it a secret
因为我被告知要保守秘密
I want to protect him
我想保护他
is that so
是这样吗
ha
哈
But I no longer know what is right
但我已经不知道 什么是对的了
this is me
这就是我
that night
那晚
Gomitsu was brought to Gominsu
Gomitsu被带到Gominsu
Isn't there anyone, hey?
没有人吗，嘿？
There's someone here
这里有人
save this man
救救这个人
please
请
Misu's friend?
米苏的朋友？
Please give me a call
请给我打电话
My brother is injured
我哥哥受伤了
Can't even walk
连走路都不能
tell me to call you
告诉我给你打电话
please
请
This madman really deserves to be killed
这个疯子 确实该杀了
Don't come here again
别再来这里了
i had to call
我不得不打电话
Just say I didn't say it
就说我没说过吧
- If you say you don't know... - It doesn't matter
- 如果你说你不知道.. - 没关系
Stay tuned because it's coming
请继续关注，因为它即将到来
if you find out later
如果你以后发现
Mom will hate me
妈妈会恨我的
I'm really tired of chasing that guy, I'm dying
我真的厌倦了追寻 那个家伙，我快要死了
Should I hit that guy?
我该打那家伙吗？
What
什么
I couldn't walk at all, I could only lie down
我根本无法行走，只能躺着
Am I going to tear him to pieces now ?
我现在就去把 他撕成碎片吗？
Quiet
安静
not even breathing
甚至不呼吸
impossible
不可能
I need a police station, Misu
我需要一个警察局，Misu
it won't happen
它不会发生
What a great opportunity!
多么好的机会啊！
try to control yourself
尝试控制自己
Not yet
这还没有
Are people dead?
人们死了吗？
He's dead anyway
反正已经死了
Can the police come and revive him?
警察能来 把他救活吗？
but also
但是也
But you have to grab it, right?
但你必须抓住它，对吧？
to whom?
给谁？
Did you see the defendant's face?
你看到被告的脸了吗？
Didn't you see?
你没看到吗？
Did you see that?
你看见了吗？
Did you see who it was?
你看到是谁了吗？
Misu
米苏
check it out
一探究竟
my brother..
我的兄弟..
Gominsu did that garbage
Gominsu做了那些垃圾
Don't let others see or notice
不要让别人看到 或注意到
I chose a place out of sight
我选了一个看不到的地方
I'm afraid that others will see me, haha
我很怕别人看到我， 哈哈
What a disappointment our family is.
我们的家人是多么令人失望的人
I'm for those people
我是为了那些人
What an insignificant existence
多么微不足道的存在
I'm scared that others will notice
我很害怕别人会注意到
hell boy
地狱男孩
Please help me
请帮我
At this point, Gominsu can end
至此，Gominsu就可以结束了
I am confident to complete
我有信心完成
but not yet
但尚未
The real culprit may be caught
真正的罪魁祸首可能会被抓获
How did you do it?
你是怎样做的？
he was not arrested
他没有被捕
(Bangbang Teahouse)
（邦邦茶馆）
What did Kim Hye Yeon say?
金惠妍说了什么？
Why?
为什么？
Not Wuguang
不是五光
The culprit is not Wuguang
罪魁祸首不是五光
witness
证人
true witness
真实见证人
He just wrote what he saw in the novel
他只是写了他在小说中看到的内容
The culprit is a man
罪魁祸首是一个男人
The only person who knows that face is Hou Guang
唯一认识那张脸的人 是后光
Yes
是的
teacher
老师
i believe in euben
我相信尤本
What’s wrong with you?
你怎么了？
teacher
老师
I'm scared
我很害怕
Be sure to say what he said
一定要说出他说的话
Sun Al...
孙艾尔..
explain
说
Say it quickly
快点说
Anyway, I think something happened to Son El
无论如何，我认为Son El 出了什么事
what have you found?
你发现了什么？
When, where and what did you see ?
您何时、何地、看到了什么 ？
He came down from school earlier
他早些时候从学校下来
He climbed up the hill behind the village
他爬上村后的小山
The teacher didn't return the ring
老师没有归还戒指
(small door)
（小门）
no no
不，不
Because the ashes of the school teacher were scattered there
因为学校老师的骨灰撒在那里
move there
搬到那里
Sorry, I have to leave
对不起，我要走了
I really experienced it like this
真的真的就这样经历了
but..
但..
Sun E
孙鄂
No need to search extensively
无需大量搜索
I called Shanai's home, but they haven't come back yet
我给善爱家里打了电话，但 他们还没有回来
Even though I called the police
尽管我报警了
The defendant has been captured and nothing will happen
被告已被抓获， 不会有任何事情发生
Every time you go out
每次出门
But the teacher
但老师
I..
我..
Without further ado, you stay there
事不宜迟，你呆在那里
I will come
我会来
my mother is gone
我妈妈走了
The last place...
最后一个地方..
The side of the mountain where Li Jing'e's bones are scattered
李景娥尸骨散落的 山边
you must inform the police
你必须通知警察
After finding Bahaisu
找到巴海苏后
Go to Baden Detective No. 8 quickly.
去巴登侦探八号很快
Can it be done?
能做到吗？
Not versatile enough
不够通用
(small door)
（小门）
Bais
巴伊斯
- What ?
- 什么 ？
Soon Al... Soon Al...
很快艾尔..很快艾尔..
sunshine air
阳光空气
Sun E
孙鄂
(Wujiang Police Station)
（吴江派出所）
Oh my God, why are you here?
天哪，为什么在这里..
Save me, little uncle
救救我吧，小叔叔
I think something fishy is going on
我觉得有些可疑的事情发生了
sunshine air
阳光空气
Are you really here?
真的在这里吗？
Sun E
孙鄂
How are you?
你还好吗？
Run away quickly
赶紧逃跑
run away
逃跑
Hey
嘿
Li Sheng'er, hurry up
李升儿快点
mr san el
桑埃尔先生
teacher
老师
The defendant then
被告人随后
Can Su wait here?
苏能在这里等吗？
Yes
是的
Sun E
孙鄂
- Sun Al
- 孙阿尔
I got it
我得到了它
The defendant is Gomin Supa, what's going on?
被告是Gomin Supa， 这是怎么回事？
nothing happened
什么都没发生
Hey hey hey, try to control yourself
嘿嘿嘿，试着控制一下自己
- Hurry, hurry up and get the kid to the hospital - Yes
- 快点、快点送孩子去医院 - 是的
- let's go - hurry up
-我们走吧 -快点
one two three
一二三
- I'll take it with me - Okay
- 我会带着它 - 好吧
(Please do not enter to accept the survey)
（请勿进入接受调查）
i believe in euben
我相信尤本
tramp believes
流浪汉相信
Beware_ _
当心 _
But the teacher
但老师
I..
我..
No matter what, I want to keep searching
无论如何我都想继续寻找
help me
帮我
earlier in the mountains
早些时候在山上
I saw the way Sun-e looked at me
我看到Sun-e看着我的 眼神
looks very scary
看起来非常可怕
I think I've become a very bad person
我想我已经成为一个非常坏的人了
teacher
老师
in other words..
换句话说..
I don't know if this is my chance
我不知道这是否是我的机会
don't move and surrender
不要动并投降
Put your hands up and come down, hey
举起双手下来，嘿
(Bangbang Teahouse)
（邦邦茶馆）
(Women who study are more dangerous)
（读书的女人更危险）
This guy
这家伙
"A Stranger I Met"
《我遇见的一个陌生人》
Who is the culprit?
罪魁祸首到底是谁？
Why do you ask me this?
你问我这个干嘛？
Another person died
又一个人死了
I'm in the same class as you
我和你在同一个班
A good boy died in an abandoned house
一个好孩子 死在废弃的房子里
Otherwise, Li Cheng'e will be dead.
不然李承娥就死定了
come out
出来
Your registration information Teacher certificate
您的注册资料 教师证书
Are they all fake?
难道都是假的吗？
Last job Last address I found everything you wrote
上一份工作 上一份地址 我找到了你写的所有内容
but he was never born
但他从未出生
"A Stranger I Met"
《我遇见的一个陌生人》